FAISAL SALIFU

WEB DEVELOPER

phaisalsalif@gmail.com

+233 55 862 8473

O Dekingraphix

DekinOLinux

My Portfolio

Faisal Salif

Ghana-Accra (Spintex comm18)

Skills

- Graphics Design
- Microsoft Office
- UX/UI design (Figma & XD)
- JavaScript
- Front end
- Back end
- Typing
- Communication
- Team Player
- Time management
- Good Listener

Education

CODETRAIN AFRICA

Present
Full-Stack Development

UDEMY

2022
PHP & MYSQL | ETHICAL HACKING
& CYBER SECURITY

CHINA WATER AND ELECTRICAL
2013 – 2015
SOIL, ASPHALT & CONCRETE
TESTING

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced developer proficient with 3 years' experience in full-stack development, with a strong focus on problem-solving.

My objective is simply to be the best engineer that I can be and to contribute to the technology industry all that I know and can do.

I am dedicated to perfecting my craft by learning from more experienced developers, remaining humble, and continuously making strides to learn all that I can about software development. I believe that my understanding of problem-solving is also a skill that I have, and will continue to contribute to my overall success as developer.

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Dekin Graphix

2022 - Present

Freelancer:

- Build and maintain of full stack web app, Mobile app, using the MERN stack technologies
- Development of Application Programming Interface (Restful)
- Designing of graphics such as Logo, Flyer, Poster and more
- Tech Stack: React , React Native, TailwindCSS , Firebase , Node JS, Mongo DB, Python

Samak Technology

2021-2022

Full-stack Developer:

- Build and maintain Full-stack websites, Mobile apps, Creating API's
- Technologies including React, TailwindCSS, Node JS, Mongo DB, Php, MySQL, JavaScript, Saas, Firebase, React Native,

Viqx Gh

2019-2020

Frontend Developer

- Build and maintain websites using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, React to create user-friendly interfaces and implement functionality.
- Technologies including, JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, API, React

China Water and Electrical Company - Ghana

2017-2018

Administrative Assistant:

- Schedule appointments and maintain calendars
- Schedule and coordinate staff and other meetings
- Prepare communications, such as memos, emails, invoices, reports and agreements.
- Create and maintain filing systems, both electronic and physical.

TECH STACK

Frontend:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React

CSS Framework:

TailwindCSS, Bootstrap

Backend:

Node JS, PHP, Express

Databases:

Mongo Db, MySQL

Mobile:

React Native

Tools:

Vscode, Git, Bracket

Design:

Figma, Photoshop, Adobe XD

Operating System:

Linux, Windows

REFERENCES

Available upon request.

China Water and Electrical Company - Ghana

2016

Assistant Laboratory Technician:

- Conduct testing on soil and asphalt samples according to established procedures and standards, ensuring accurate and reliable results.
- Clean, calibrate, and maintain laboratory equipment and instruments used for soil and asphalt testing to ensure their proper functioning and accuracy.
- Record test results and observations accurately, organize data, and assist in analyzing and summarizing findings for reports and presentations.
- Assist in quality control measures by following established protocols, monitoring processes, and reporting any deviations or anomalies to supervisors.

RECENT PROJECTS

MYRYD

- Technologies: React, Redux toolkit, TailwindCSS, Node JS, Mongo DB, Express JS
- MYRYD is an easy-to-use online platform for booking bus tickets. It offers realtime seat availability, multiple payment options, and ticket management features, ensuring a hassle-free booking experience for travelers.
- Link to project https://github.com/DekinOLinux/MRYD

ECOMMERCE APP

- Technologies: React, TailwindCSS, FakestoreAPI, and Redux toolkit.
- Shopright is a user-friendly ecommerce platform where users can browse and purchase a wide range of products online. It provides secure payment options and reliable order management, making online shopping convenient and enjoyable.
- Link to project https://github.com/DekinOLinux/ecommerceApp

CINEMAN (Movie Thriller Platform)

- Technologies : React, TailwindCSS , TMDB api,
- Streamflix is a comprehensive movie thriller streaming platform that offers a
 vast collection of new movies and TV shows from TMDM API. Users can enjoy
 on-demand thriller streaming, personalized recommendations.
- Link to project https://github.com/DekinOLinux/CINEMAN